<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>swift project – New Releases</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/releases/</link><description>Recent content in New Releases on swift project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://swift-project.github.io/blog/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Release of 0.9.4</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2020/01/03/release-of-0.9.4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2020/01/03/release-of-0.9.4/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We recommend to keep the latest 093 until 094 works for you. See
&lt;code>copyswiftdata&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} .&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="version-numbering">Version numbering&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The 4th component of the version number is now based on the number of
code changes, instead of the build date, so the full version numbers
should be easier to read:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Example old version number: 0.9.3.912280030&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Example new version number: 0.9.4.24&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="qt-514">Qt 5.14&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Version 0.9.4 of swift now uses Qt 5.14.x (or later). This means&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>swift layout on 4k display might look different&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IMPORTANT: if you use external style sheets these may need to be
adjusted. We have made some smaller adjustments to the qss (swift
stylesheet) and the external style sheets needs to be updated to
reflect those changes. See ALSO BELOW!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some audio issues are hopefully fixed like the MIC 100% issue on
Windows&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="wasapi-driver">WASAPI driver&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The WASAPI driver caused problems/crashes for some people. We have
disabled the driver per default. To use it just copy it back, see
Troubleshoot voice (&lt;code>troubleshootvoice&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} )
WASAPI&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="x-plane">X-Plane&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The xSwiftBus version compatibility check has been made smarter,
which should result in fewer false positive warnings being
generated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The sim frame rate can be seen in swift's simulator info screen.
This is important when flying online, due to X-Plane's time warping
at frame rates under 20 FPS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Log messages when the terrain probe fails to find the ground
elevation. This may be useful to diagnose planes going underground.
Also TCAS can be disabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to disable terrain probe. This may be useful to diagnose
performance problems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fixes for T778, underground XPlane aircraft&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="flightgear">Flightgear&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Traffic will be displayed within Flightgears maps (Nasal map,
Nav-Displays etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introducing a more strict compatibility check, which checks the
swift&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;Flightgear API version on connection via dbus.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other aircraft on the ground are now really set to Flightgear's
ground altitude and not hovering anymore.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="fixed-issues-login-required">Fixed issues (login required)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>List of fixed bugs:
&lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/jl6HKojM8qtF/">https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/jl6HKojM8qtF/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And of course all 093 fixes are included
&lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/KJbxELvKISgX/">https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/KJbxELvKISgX/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Also fixed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>TEMP WORKAROUND: Disabled crashpad for Linux as it is buggy (will be
re-enabled as soon as it is fixed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SSL libs no longer depend on VisualStudio 2010 redistributable DLLs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Issues with closed floating windows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tabs with no name must not cause an ASSERT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FSD messages we do not need ignored&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NaN assert fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>audio settings on remote UI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>no need to stop/start audio on remote UI anymore&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Q_UNREACHABLE in other networks if pilot rating is unknown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Misc. interpolation/ground elevation issues have been fixed:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ground elevation improvements: T773&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using &lt;em>-1&lt;/em> instead of NOT for inverse FS pitch/bank (same as vPilot
and xPilot)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Flight plan templates: T733&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Timestamps for XPlane logs, hopefully helping when investigating
issues&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Splitter for ATIS T783&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="style-sheet-changes">Style sheet changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Those are the latest style sheet changes, so you can adjust custom style
sheets&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Release of 0.9.3</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/10/26/release-of-0.9.3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/10/26/release-of-0.9.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="swift-093-is-the-1st-afv-version">swift 093 is the 1st AFV version&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>swift 093 is the first version of swift with AFV integrated. This is released as alpha version, as we still expect some issues. Your feedback is welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Again, currently we are in a TESTING stage, &amp;quot;alpha&amp;quot; software, see &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_release_life_cycle#Alpha">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_release_life_cycle#Alpha&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discord support: &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/ndqBvHQ">https://discord.gg/ndqBvHQ&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download: &lt;a href="https://datastore.swift-project.org/page/publicartifacts.php">https://datastore.swift-project.org/page/publicartifacts.php&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
The 0.9.3 versions do NOT work with the old VATSIM voice servers, only with AFV.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="fixed-issues-in-093">Fixed issues in 093&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>See &lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/KJbxELvKISgX/">https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/KJbxELvKISgX/&lt;/a> (login required)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-afv">What is AFV?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Audio for VATSIM (AFV) is the new voice codec for VATSIM, more
information can be found here and here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VATSIM will be offline for scheduled maintenance for 24 hours, from
2019-10-13 2000z until 2019-10-14 2000z. During that time, the network
will migrate over to the new codec, and the old codec will stop working.
If you want to continue using swift 0.9.2 beta after that time, you will
need to install an extra piece of software: the AFV standalone client,
which works on Windows only.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wasapi-audio-plugin-windows">WASAPI audio plugin (Windows)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PLEASE READ: &lt;a href="https://swift-project.github.io/docs/installation/troubleshootvoice/">Troubleshoot voice&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="voice-room-connect-error-swift-092">Voice room connect error (swift 0.9.2)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you use 0.9.2 or earlier, you might see that error. It happens
because VATSIM now uses some invalid voice room URLs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Solution: use 0.9.3. if you dare, but read the above.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/wrongvoiceroom.png" alt="image">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Release of 0.9.2</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/05/21/release-of-0.9.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/05/21/release-of-0.9.2/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Reset your matching settings, then save them (Reset ALL and SAVE settings). Then set it according to your needs and save again, see Matching settings, using models without mapping entry / no DB entry. Most likely you also need to save your audio settings again, as those have changed and need to be updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>XPlane users, if you install a test version (developer/aka alpha version) you have to manually install XSwiftBus! You can download it from the alpha download page, see Download developer and alpha versions from datastore .&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We recommend you install 0.9.2 parallel to 0.9.1, then test it and if
your are happy with it, uninstall 0.9.1. There is no need to re-create
your model set, you can copy settings and data from other swift
installations at any time in the wizard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;code>copyswiftdata&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fixesfeatures">Fixes/Features&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>List of bug fixes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A first version of matching script, see &lt;code>ms&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Airline groups now can be configured for their matching behaviour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Logged interpolation now exports values as kml which can be verified in Google Earth. See how to log. interpolation here: Tracing interpolation. You will find the log files here: Find swift log files, crashdump files, interpolation log. files, the kml files are in the same directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Linear interpolation was broken, hopefully now fixed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DB values can be used for CG/vertical offset&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forcible closed connection, see T698. In order to investigate we have added a network packets statistics which will hopefully help us to find the issue, still under investigation . But when you face the issue, sending the statistics file from the log directory will help us - Find swift log files, crashdump files, interpolation log. files. See Tracing network packets (FSD log) and network statistics how to enable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The COM1/2 features are available as experimental feature: T609 T675 See Integrate COM unit, sync with cockpit COM unit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto publish, swift can automatically &amp;quot;learn&amp;quot; values for DB updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Own aircraft values can be used for ground elevation, see &amp;quot;record gnd. position&amp;quot;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spline interpolation bugs fixed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can set the focus for the overlay messages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>X-Plane fixes
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Some TCAS displays were not workin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aircraft labels were too small on very high resolution displays&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voice ATIS is now disabled whenever XSwiftBus is enabled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed weather as NOAA has changed its format&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed support for international characters in text chat (see how to choose a text codec)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incognito mode for streaming: Incognito mode (hide names for streaming)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Avoid FG crash with no model set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for SVFR et.al.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flight plans can be downloaded from SimBrief&lt;/li>
&lt;li>more detailed XPlane settings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>advanced login screen to modify/set livery, model string and partner callsign (pilot/co-pilot), see Advanced login popup (since 0.9.2)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the sort order of text messages can be changed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Release of 0.9.0</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/04/27/release-of-0.9.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/04/27/release-of-0.9.0/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Issues: &lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/7nqUaT07BtX8/">https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/7nqUaT07BtX8/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Release of 0.9.1</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/04/27/release-of-0.9.1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/blog/2019/04/27/release-of-0.9.1/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
Testers/alpha users need to manually install XSwiftBus (download and copy)
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Version 0.9.1 fixes some bugs
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the critical FSD packet bug, see &lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/phame/post/view/14/crash/">https://dev.swift-project.org/phame/post/view/14/crash/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some XPlane aircraft issues, causing aircraft not correctly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>removed from XP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fixed an UI based crash which could crash swift mapping tool&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when floating windows&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>now hot plug and play for joystick hotkeys&lt;/li>
&lt;li>swift does now proceed with connection to xswiftbus even if versions do not match&lt;/li>
&lt;li>XPlane CSL no longer stops parsing &lt;code>xsb\_aircraft.txt&lt;/code> if an error occurred.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for various other fixes see full list of issues fixed: &lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/E91DVCMxGNWl/">https://dev.swift-project.org/maniphest/query/E91DVCMxGNWl/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We recommend you install 0.9.1 parallel to 0.9.0, then test it and if
your are happy with it, uninstall 0.9.0. There is no need to re-create
your model set, you can copy settings and data from other swift
installations at any time in the wizard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See: https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/swiftinstallation/copyswiftdata/&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>