<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>swift project – Aviation</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/knowhow/aviation/</link><description>Recent content in Aviation on swift project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://swift-project.github.io/docs/knowhow/aviation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Aviation altitude (vertical distance)</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/knowhow/aviation/verticaldistance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/knowhow/aviation/verticaldistance/</guid><description>
&lt;p>::: {.note}
::: {.title}
Note
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;p>see also geodetic height
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130626035126/http://www.gmat.unsw.edu.au/snap/gps/clynch_pdfs/coordcvt.pdf">http://web.archive.org/web/20130626035126/http://www.gmat.unsw.edu.au/snap/gps/clynch_pdfs/coordcvt.pdf&lt;/a>
page 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.esri.com/news/arcuser/0703/geoid1of3.html">http://www.esri.com/news/arcuser/0703/geoid1of3.html&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;what is MSL&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>True This is the actual, physical distance between the aircraft and the
Altitude mean sea level. It is what you would see if you could actually
measure the distance with a very big ruler. In the real world,
pilots usually do not use this, as it can usually only be measured
approximately by GPS. In the virtual world (which is what swift is
modelling), &lt;strong>it is what we generally use when talking to FSD and
the simulators.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Absolute This is the actual, physical distance between the aircraft and the
Height AGL ground directly beneath it. This could be as measured by a radar
altimeter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Altitude This is the altitude above mean sea level as measured by a pressure
QNH altimeter on the aircraft. In order to relate this to any other
type of altitude, two data must be known: the actual atmospheric
QNH (e.g. obtained by METAR), and the QNH setting which the pilot
has dialled into their altimeter; these two data might be
different, so both must be known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flight Besides the fact that the unit of measurement is always hundreds of
Level feet, the only difference between Flight Level and Altitude QNH is
that the QNH setting is always fixed at 1013.2hPa or 29.92inHg.
Therefore one datum must be known: the actual atmospheric QNH (e.g.
from METAR).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reference-elevation">Height QFE This is the height above a reference elevation at e.g. an airport.
Height QFE differs from Altitude QNH only in that the reference
point is an elevation above or below mean sea level, rather than
mean sea level itself (MSL+0). Therefore three data must be known:
the actual atmospheric QNH, the pilot&amp;rsquo;s QNH setting, and the QFE
reference elevation.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition, an altitude can be either an indicated altitude of an
actual aircraft or other object in real time, or a nominal altitude such
as entered in a flight plan. These two groups, multiplied by the five
above, gives a total of ten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This matrix shows the data which would be needed to convert between
different types of altitude:&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> **True **Absolute **Altitude **Flight **Height QFE**
Altitude** Height AGL** QNH** Level**
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>True Ground Actual QNH and Actual QNH Actual QNH,
Altitude&lt;/strong> elevation set QNH set QNH, and
QFE elevation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Absolute Ground Ground Ground Ground Ground
Height AGL&lt;/strong> elevation elevation x2 elevation, elevation elevation,
actual QNH, and actual actual QNH,
and set QNH QNH set QNH, and
QFE elevation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Altitude Actual QNH Ground Actual QNH x2 Actual QNH Actual QNH x2,
QNH&lt;/strong> and set QNH elevation, and set QNH x2 x2 and set set QNH x2,
actual QNH, QNH and QFE
and set QNH elevation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Flight Actual QNH Ground Actual QNH x2 Actual QNH Actual QNH x2,
Level&lt;/strong> elevation and and set QNH x2 set QNH, and
actual QNH QFE elevation&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="qfe-elevation--qfe-elevation--elevation">&lt;strong>Height Actual QNH, Ground Ground Actual QNH Actual QNH x2,
QFE&lt;/strong> set QNH, and elevation, elevation, x2, set set QNH, and
QFE actual QNH, actual QNH, QNH, and QFE elevation
elevation set QNH, and set QNH, and QFE &lt;br>
QFE elevation QFE elevation elevation&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Docs: ICAO DB - official ICAO codes</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/knowhow/aviation/icaodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/knowhow/aviation/icaodb/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.icao.int/publications/doc8643/pages/search.aspx">https://www.icao.int/publications/doc8643/pages/search.aspx&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>