<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>swift project – swift alpha program (swift alpha and developer versions)</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/</link><description>Recent content in swift alpha program (swift alpha and developer versions) on swift project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Accounts explained and how to troubleshoot</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/accounts/</guid><description>
&lt;p>::: {.todo}
This page needs major rework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>order to participate in swift testing a few accounts are needed and
hopefully this here will help to understand what they are and whom to
ask.
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we can help, we need to understand what the problem is. We
received requests like &amp;quot;I cannot login&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;I have not been approved&amp;quot;,
etc. Please tell us what you are talking about. What is not working&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downloading the software? The login to slack? The login to this site
here? Below you find some information about the different accounts,
please let us know where you face the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: {.warning}
::: {.title}
Warning
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure you can receive email from us and the invitations for slack,
this site here etc. do NOT go to your SPAM folder.
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downloading the software Downloading the software for alpha test:
&lt;a href="https://datastore.swift-project.org/">https://datastore.swift-project.org/&lt;/a> Most users login with VATSIM SSO.
If this is the first time, a user credential will be created. This
credential will be approved by one of the swift admins Typical problems:
Some users just login with VATSIM SSO, never contact us, and just
disappear. Those accounts will never be approved. Become a alpha tester,
or alpha tester for VATSIM You need to contact us, nothing will happen
before we have your full real name, VATSIM id (if applicable), and a
valid email address When you are becoming a member of the testing team,
you will receive 2 invitations (emails): One for this site here:
&lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org/">https://dev.swift-project.org/&lt;/a> This is required for &amp;quot;bug reports&amp;quot;,
... One for slack:: this is the most agile form in getting in touch
with us to interactively resolve problems. Did you get the emails. Did
you verify your account here? Also we need to forward your credentials
to VATSIM who will allow you testing with a development client in the
network. Legal information: In doing this you deal with 3 parties: Us,
legal info is here. VATSIM, you have to check their legal information,
and if you install slack, also the corresponding information there. You
are absolutely free to register here or with slack. It is your personal
decision. We only use slack at this time because it is convenient, we
are not related in any kind of business association. No login with
VATSIM If you see this, VATSIM has not yet approved your id. If this
does not disappear within 3 days, please contact us. We then crosscheck.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Adding icons (airlines, VAs, other organizations etc.)</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/newicons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/newicons/</guid><description>
&lt;p>::: {.important}
::: {.title}
Important
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add new icons as task, see below
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Read &lt;code>airlineicons&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} for format, naming
etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you have multiple icons please use a container like
[zip]{.title-ref}, [rar]{.title-ref} or similar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sign the (all online)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yes, a feature for an easy upload was nice. If you could do that,
see &lt;code>opentasks&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} and
&lt;code>gi&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} . Currently you have to do it as
described in the next step!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can just click here to create a new task. Just drag and drop the
icons into the task or use the file button.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Alpha Q and A (questions and answers)</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/qa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/qa/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="i-am-confused-about-all-the-sites">I am confused about all the sites&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can be explained: * This site (&lt;a href="https://dev.swift-project.org">https://dev.swift-project.org&lt;/a>) is
about swift development and bug reports * The datastore
(&lt;a href="https://datastore.swift-project.org">https://datastore.swift-project.org&lt;/a>) contains the mappings and alpha
users can download the swift development versions. * The alpha
downloads can be downloaded from
&lt;a href="https://datastore.swift-project.org/page/alpha.html">https://datastore.swift-project.org/page/alpha.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-sso">What is SSO?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>SSO means single sign on, you do not need an extra username/password but
you can use your VATSIM credentials.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="i-cannot-login-with-with-vatsim-sso">I cannot login with with VATSIM SSO&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Do a simple test, try to login to &lt;a href="https://forums.vatsim.net">https://forums.vatsim.net&lt;/a> If SSO
does not work with you? * If not, there is a problem with your VATSIM
credentials - you need to clarify with VATSIM. * If this works and not
with datastore, let us know * &lt;strong>Other hint:&lt;/strong> if you have a 6 digit
VATSIM id, try to add a leading 0: 123456 -&amp;gt; 0123456 * If this still
does not work, contact us via&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Please read &lt;code>installation&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} chapter
directory concept.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="general">General&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>My account is not approved yet. We approve users step by step (in
waves). We want to handle user requests/issue before we accept new
users testing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Where can I file bug reports?
&lt;code>Here &amp;lt;reportingbugs&amp;gt;&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}, check the
&lt;code>status page &amp;lt;status&amp;gt;&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} first.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why is there no voice in the YouTube tutorials? Simple, matter of
time. They are subtitled because subtitles can be easily added and
adjusted - so resources is the reason&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why is A and B not happening, happening faster etc.? Resources,
easiest way of speeding up things, join and do it. Are capacity
limit is reached.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I did not get a response to my query? Be patient, or ask again.
Hobby project, limited resources (maybe we should set up a telephone
hotline holding queue as in professional projects]]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the alpha chat room, how to disable all the email notifications?
Go to the top of the page, settings, you can change it there&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="updates">Updates&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check the &lt;code>status page &amp;lt;status&amp;gt;&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} to
see if something is ready&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Currently you have to manually download, improved feature in
development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can override a swift installation, or just delete the folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close swift before updating.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>General swift Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>faq&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: alpha status</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/status/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/status/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Also check &lt;code>qa&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Public &lt;code>whatsnew&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;} Public versions&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>201907xx &lt;code>092&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201905xx &lt;code>091&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201904xx &lt;code>090&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201901xx &lt;code>089&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201811xx &lt;code>087&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201809xx &lt;code>086&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201808xx &lt;code>085&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201806xx &lt;code>084&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201709xx &lt;code>083&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>201704xx &lt;code>082&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>20170427 &lt;code>081&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>20170427 Workaround for MacOS &lt;code>installation&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text
role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p>
&lt;p>20170427 MacOS installer currently broken. -&amp;gt; under investigation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>20170425 Bug for bootstrap download failure -&amp;gt; under investigation&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="20170424---mandatory-description-field-issue-resolved">20170424 Mandatory description field, issue resolved&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>::: {.toctree glob=&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;Content of this chapter&amp;rdquo;}
./*
:::&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Jenkins Download</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/jenkinsdownload/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/alpha/jenkinsdownload/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="legal">Legal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By downloading Jenkins builds you agree with the sift legal terms
outlined &lt;a href="https://datastore.swift-project.org/page/legal.php">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>swift installer is being built autonomously via Jenkins Continuous
Integration (&lt;a href="https://build.swift-project.org">https://build.swift-project.org&lt;/a>). For every published
change a set of per-configured tasks called jobs is executed to test for
build errors, run unit tests and produces a new installer. Usually at
the end of a development cycle, those installers will be made available
to the different release channels. But it might also be necessary to
directly download from Jenkins for short test and fix cycles.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-primary" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Important&lt;/h4>
Installing from Jenkins is a bit different than via the official release
channels. The differences will be explained here.
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While we are in a closed testing phase, all installer downloads are
restricted. This means, an extra account to log into Jenkins is
required. Anonymous download is not possible. As soon as you received
your login details, log yourself in and change your password. This can
be done either by clicking on the small arrow next to your name after
login.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>or simply by using the url
&lt;a href="https://build.swift-project.org/user/">https://build.swift-project.org/user/&lt;/a>&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/configure. Don't
forget to replace &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; with your actual user name.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downloading-the-installer">Downloading the Installer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The different jobs listed in Jenkins have a very specific pattern, which
can look confusing to someone not being used to the development process
of swift. Jobs are created, modified and deleted on a daily basis. But
the good news is, that as tester, you don't need to know which job will
have the installer for you to test. The developer will either tell you
the job name or pass you directly the link to the download.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The link will usually guide you to the jobs archived artifacts (file
names are examples only and might change):&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Artifact&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>swiftinstaller-windows-64-0.8.4.806011712.exe&lt;/td>
&lt;td>swift installer&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>swiftsymbols-windows-64-0.8.4.806011712.tar.gz&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Symbols package (can be ignored)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>xswiftbus-windows-64-0.8.4.806011712.7z&lt;/td>
&lt;td>XSwiftBus X-Plane Plugin&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>swift installer is required for everyone. XSwiftBus is only necessary if
you are going to use X-Plane. Note that this version of X-Plane only
contains the so called thin plugin. So only the binaries for a specific
toolset of compiler, architecture and OS, e.g. only MSVC Windows 64 bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>so you go from the start page to the relevant version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>then the build number, &amp;quot;red&amp;quot; dots mean the build failed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>then you see the installer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For &lt;em>swift&lt;/em> itself, the install process is not different compared to the
release channels. The major difference is that, xswiftbus is not
downloaded automatically for you, but you need to extract and copy the
downloaded XSwiftBus package content yourself into the path
&lt;code>&amp;lt;X-Plane Root&amp;gt;/Resources/plugins/xswiftbus&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="updating">Updating&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is always recommended to uninstall the previous version of swift
before installing the new version. All data and settings will be kept as
long as you install in the same directory. See also
&lt;code>copyswiftdata&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;quot;ref&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>