<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>swift project – Create mappings for swift</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/smt/createmappings/</link><description>Recent content in Create mappings for swift on swift project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/smt/createmappings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Effectively and efficiently create mappings</title><link>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/smt/createmappings/effmappings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-project.github.io/docs/help/smt/createmappings/effmappings/</guid><description>
&lt;p>First of all, swift mapping is about quality, not quantity. So just
create a mapping which is wrong is not the goal. However, there are some
tricks to speed up the mapping process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="use-pre-selected-models">Use pre-selected models&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The process becomes much faster if you but models on the stash which
have something in common. That can be the &amp;quot;distributor&amp;quot;, the &amp;quot;ICAO
code&amp;quot; or even multiple attributes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Here I select all [B732]{.title-ref} of the [BVAI]{.title-ref}
distribution. So I already know I will have only those models on the
stash. Stash those&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/All_B732_BVAI.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Now on the stash, I select all of the, and assign [BVAI]{.title-ref}
by pressing [distributor]{.title-ref} to all selected. So by one
click, the distributor is set for all models.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/BVAI_distributor.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Same for the aircraft ICAO, select [B732]{.title-ref}, [aircraft
ICAO]{.title-ref}, and all models have the correct ICAO code&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/B732_ICAO.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>With these 2 simple steps, you have fixed distributor and aircraft
ICAO, now only the livery/airline is missing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now we check the airlines one by one, remember it is about quality.
A good share will already be correct.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whenever I have found some correct ones, I select and publish them
(small steps)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/Published_models.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Then I remove them from the stash, so I have only those left which I
still need to handle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After a few iterations I have one model left I still need to
resolve. In my case [ModelConverterX]{.title-ref} could be used to
check the model (what it really is)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/Model_ConverterX.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you are unable to resolve the livery, you can provide at [temp
livery]{.title-ref}. This is a special livery for those aircraft
still need a correct livery assigned. In such a case &amp;quot;specialists&amp;quot;
can select those models and add. the missing information&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/Temp_livery.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summary: This examples shows how you can quickly write mappings for a
larger number of aircraft. You do not need to follow each step, it is to
give you an idea about mapping techniques.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="using-models-of-a-arbitrary-directory">Using models of a arbitrary directory&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Maybe you want to download models and do the mappings &lt;strong>without&lt;/strong>
installing them for your flight simulator. In that case you can use a
little trick and use &lt;code>force reload from directory&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/forcereload.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when I install the [BVAI]{.title-ref} models (for example) in
&lt;code>C:\temp\BVAI&lt;/code> I can load my own models from there. Then you can create
the mapping for those models without installing them into you flight
simulator directories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://img.swift-project.org/Loading_from_directory.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately you have to reload you simulator models again, if you want
to have those from the simulator back. But could also save the models to
a file (like for a backup), and later load them again.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>